Guide to the Mary C. Schlosser Collection of Harriet Beecher Stowe, 1838-2021 (bulk 1852-1934)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- Series IV. Realia, 1852-2021, undated
  - Wallpaper Panels
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin," the death of Uncle Tom, with caption, undated (Folder 12.10)
- Series V. Audiovisual Media, [1968?]-2014
  - Compact disc: Gelber, Stanley & Kimberley Vaughn, Lord Tom the Musical, 2013 (Folder 2.22)
  - DVD-R: Uncle Tom's Cabin, directed by Harry A. Pollard, 1928, 2014 (Folder 2.23)
  - Phonograph record: "Off The Record: The Stenographer / Uncle Tom's Cabin," Camden, NJ: Victor Talking Machine Co., undated; [10 in, 78 rpm] (Box 15)
  - Phonograph record: "Uncle Tom's Cabin: Original Motion Picture Soundtrack," composed by Peter Thomas, lyrics by Aldo Von Pinelli, directed by Geza Von Radvanui. An Aldo Von Pinelli Production-Melodie-Film. Chicago: Mercury Records Corporation, [1968?]; [12 in, 13 1/3 rpm] (Box 15)
- Series VI. Beecher Family Papers, 1836-1947
  - Letter from Beecher, Catherine to Thomas Dick, with card from Calvin E. Stowe, 1836 May (Folder 2.24)
  - Letter from Beecher, Catherine to Horace Greeley, Esq., 1851 Jan 28 (Folder 2.25)
  - Letter from Beecher, Catherine to Hon. Judge Lane, 1847 Aug 26 (Folder 2.26)
  - Letter from Beecher, Catherine to Anna Lynch, 1850 Jul 12 (Folder 2.27)
  - Letter from Beecher, Catherine to "Mrs. Stone,", 1852 Jan 5 (Folder 2.28)
  - Letter from Beecher, Catherine to Rev. Dr. [Bennet?] Tyler, 1850 Jun 1 (Folder 2.29)
  - Letter from Beecher, Catherine to "My dear Virgia,", 1870s (Folder 2.30)
  - Letter from Hooker, Isabella Beecher to Eva Douglas Wise, [1891 Apr?] (Folder 2.31)
  - Letter from Hooker, Isabella Beecher to "My dear friend,", [1876?] Apr 26 (Folder 2.32)
  - Letter from Stowe, Lyman Beecher to Emanuel Hertz, 1933 Apr 17 (Folder 2.33)
  - Letter from Stowe, Lyman Beecher to Emanuel Hertz, 1934 May 24 (Folder 2.33)
  - Letter from Stowe, Lyman Beecher to "Mr. Roberts,", 1947 Jun 2 (Folder 2.33)
- Series VII. Catalogued Material, 1838-2017
  Rare books and pamphlets, as well as a number of periodicals and broadsides, were separated from the collection and catalogued as part of the Archives and Special Collections Library Rare Book Collection. These items can be found by searching the Vassar College Libraries online catalog for the Mary C. Schlosser Collection of Harriet Beecher Stowe, as well as listed at the end of this guide as Series VII. Catalogued Materials.
  - Books
    - Aiken, George L., "Uncle Tom's Cabin," French's Standard Drama No. 218, undated; [yellow]
    - Aiken, George L., "Uncle Tom's Cabin," French's Standard Drama No. 218, [1920?]; [green, 2 copies]
    - Aiken, George L., "Uncle Tom's Cabin," Sergel's Acting Drama, [after 1901]
    - "America's Twelve Great Women Leaders During the Past Hundred Years,", 1933
    - "Aunt Mary's Picture Book: Little Eva," New York: Phil J. Cozans, undated
    - Baker, Adella, "Famous Authors of America,", circa 1898
    - "Bamboula! Black Music Before the Blues," Providence: John Hay Library, Brown University, 2017
    - "Caban F'Ewythr Twm" [Uncle Tom's Cabin], Remsen, NY: John R. Everett, 1854
    - "La Case de L'Oncle Tom," Editions Bias-Paris, 1942
    - "Iter ad Valleculam," Northampton: Kat Ran Press, 2003
    - "Lays of Liberty; or, Verse for the Times," Boston: Bela Marsh, 1854
    - "Onkel Tom's Hütte," Reutlingen: Druck und Verlag von Ensslin und Laiblin, undated
    - "Onkel Toms Hytte," Eneret: Stenders Forlag, undated
    - "Papers and Letters Presented at the First Woman's Congress of the Association for the Advancement of Women…,", 1874
    - "Pictures and Stories from Uncle Tom's Cabin," Boston: John P. Jewett & Co., circa 1853
    - Rowe, George F., "Uncle Tom's Cabin," printed for Messrs. Jarrett & Palmer, 1878
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "Beneath Thy Wings," London: Raphael Tuck & Sons, undated
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "He's Coming To-Morrow," in The Second Coming of Christ, Chicago: The Bible Institute Colportage Association, 1896 Aug 1
    - Thomas, A. E., "Uncle Tom's Cabin," revised version based on the dramatization by George L. Aiken, 1934
    - "Topsy," New York: McLoughlin Brothers Publishers, circa 1890
    - Townsend, Charles, "Uncle Tom's Cabin," New York: Harold Roorbach Publisher, 1889
    - Tucker, Louis L., "The Incomparable Beecher Family," Cincinnati: C. J. Krehbiel, 1963
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin," illustrated by Rolland H. Livingstone, Classics Illustrated No. 15, New York: Gilberton Company, Inc., circa 1950
  - Broadsides
    - "On de Oder Side of Jordan," Thomas M. Scroggy Publisher, undated
    - Tayleure, Clifton W., "The Fugitive's Experience," from The Baltimore Dispatch, undated
  - Pamphlets
    - "Annual Meeting of the Connecticut Woman Suffrage Association, Held At Hartford, September, 9, 1870. Report of the Executive Committee," Hartford: Press of Case, Lockwood & Brainard, 1871
    - Bristed, Charles Astor, "In Honorem…", circa 1870
    - "Calvin E. Stowe and Harriet Beecher Stowe his wife v. F. W. Thomas", 1853 Oct
    - "The Constitutional Rights of the Women of the United States, an Address Before the International Council of Women. Washington, D.C., March 30, 1888," Hartford, CT: Fowler & Miller Company, Printers
    - Duncan, V. and R., "Rememb'ring," New York: Irving Berlin, Inc., circa 1923
    - "Green's Juvenile Drama: Dred by Harriet Beecher Stowe," London: J. K. Green, 1856
    - Hooker, Isabella Beecher, "Memorial of the Connecticut Woman Suffrage Association to the Constitutional Convention Assembled in Hartford, Connecticut, January 1, 1902, and an Argument Theron," Hartford, CT: Plimpton Mfg. Co. Print
    - Jones, J., "Thoughts on Uncle Tom in Paradise," Chatham: A. T. Fordham, 1853
    - Kaser, Arthur Leroy, "The Filming of 'Uncle Tom's Cabin'," Chicago: T. S. Denison & Co, undated
    - Letter from Harriet Beecher Stowe to Wendell Phillips defending her father, in "Speech of Wendel Phillips,", circa 1853
    - "Notes and Documents: Harriet Beecher Stowe's Reply," reprinted from the Mississippi Valley Historical Review, 1932
    - "Report of the 24th National Anti-Slavery Festival,", 1858; [2 copies]
    - "A Sermon Delivered at the Installation of the Rev. E. E. Hale," Boston: Leonard C. Bowles, 1856
    - "The Shevvild Chap's Opinion abaht Uncle Tom's Cabin," The Shevvild Chap's Annual, 1853
    - Simons, John Shirk, "Uncle Tom's Cabin by Harriet Beecher Stowe (abridged)," Instructor Literature Series No. 296, Dansville, NY: F. A. Owens Publishing Co., circa 1918; [2 copies]
    - Simons, John Shirk, "Uncle Tom's Cabin by Harriet Beecher Stowe; condensed and retold," Instructor Literature Series No. 296, Dansville, NY: F. A. Owens Publishing Co., circa 1918
    - Simons, John Shirk, "Uncle Tom's Cabin by Harriet Beecher Stowe; condensed and retold," Instructor Literature Series No. 296, Dansville, NY: F. A. Owens Publishing Co., 1918 Jun; [3 copies]
    - Smart, Lucy Allen, "Living Portraits of Historic Women of the U.S.," New York: Paulus-Ullman Printing Corporation, undated
    - "Stories for Summer Days and Winter Nights: Uncle Tom's Cabin, for children,", undated; [2 copies]
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "Eliza," Godey's Lady's Book, 1840 Jan
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "He's Coming To-Morrow," London: The Book Society, undated
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "The Two Altars," Anti-Slavery Tracts, No. 18, circa 1852
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "The Two Altars," Liberty Tracts, No. 1, circa 1852
    - "Twilight at Uncle Tom's Cabin," by A. B. G., undated
    - "Uncle Tom in England," New York: Bruce & Brother, 1852
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin" and "Cruiskeen Lawn" song lyrics, Northampton, MA: Henson Printer & Co., undated
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin," In Life Motion Pictures, Philadelphia: S. Lubin, undated
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, A Drama in Three Acts," Webb's Juvenile Drama, undated
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin, Blackpool,", circa 1912
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin; songster," Willis & Co., undated
    - "Uncle Tom's Melodies,", circa 1850s
  - Periodicals
    - Alabama Heritage, No. 75, 2005 Winter
    - "Antiques," Antiques (p. 343), 1968 Sep
    - "The Beecher Island Annual: Sixty-Second Anniversary of the Battle of Beecher Island, Sept. 17, 18, 1868," Wray, Colorado: The Beecher Island Battle Memorial Association, 1930; [2 copies]
    - Fitzhugh, Daisy, "Lewis Clarke, the original of George Harris, the hero of 'Uncle Toms Cabin'," Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1891 Jun 20
    - Fleming, Thomas, "The Real Uncle Tom and the Unknown South He Helped Create," Financial History, 2013 Spring
    - "H. W. Beecher and H. B. Stowe," Harper's Weekly, 1869 Oct 30
    - "Henry Ward Beecher and Harriet Beecher Stowe," Illustrated Annual for 1871
    - "How 'Uncle Tom's Cabin' Was Written," The Household, 1891 Jan
    - Maurice, Arthur B., "The Play That Goes On Forever," The Mentor, 1923 Mar
    - McKean, Kenneth, "A play that once shook a nation presented in a remarkable revival. Uncle Tom's Cabin," The Stage, 1933 Jul
    - Pilcher, Veona, "The Variorum Stowe," in Theater Arts Monthly, 1926 Apr
    - Portland Transcript, 1858 Aug 7
    - "Rev. Henry Ward Beecher," Harper's Weekly, 1863 Nov 14
    - Review of "The Key to Uncle Tom's Cabin" by Harriet Beecher Stowe, in Little's Living Age, second series, 1853 Jun 18
    - Review of Uncle Tom's Cabin, Portland Transcript, 1852 Apr 3
    - Stowe, Charles Edward and Lyman Beecher, "How Mrs. Stowe Wrote Uncle Tom's Cabin," in McLure's Magazine, 1911 Apr
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "Art and Nature," in Godey's Lady's Book, 1839 Dec
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "Children," The Odd Fellow, 1849 Aug 8
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "Christ," The Youth's Companion, 1884 Jul 10
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "The Deacon's Dilemma," Portland Transcript, 1860 Dec 15
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "The Heart Has No Tears to Give: Excerpt from Uncle Tom's Cabin," Lincoln Center Theater Review, 2015 Spring
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "A Home in an Orange Grove" and review of Oldtown Folks, Portland Transcript, 1869 May 29
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "Isabelle and Her Sister Kate, and Their Cousin," in The Monthly Chronicle, 1839 Oct
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "The Ladies of Maine," New York Organ, 1852 Oct 2
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "Laughin' in Meetin'," Portland Transcript, 1872 Aug 17
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "Mark Meriden," Portland Transcript, 1841 Jun 19
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "Old Father Morris," Portland Transcript, 1838 Nov 10
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "Our Early Rose Potatoes," Portland Transcript, 1869 Oct 23
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "Our Second Girl," in Atlantic Monthly, 1868 Jan
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "A Reply," in Atlantic Monthly, 1863 Jan
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "Simon the Cyrenian," and Henry Ward Beecher, "Sermon," The Independent, 1862 Jul 31
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "Sojourner Truth, the Libyan Sibyl," in Atlantic Monthly, 1863 Apr
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "The Tea Rose," in Godey's Lady's Book, 1842 Mar
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "This Sale and the Other," The Youth's Companion, 1864 Jan 7
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "We and Our Neighbors," The Christian Union, 1874
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "What Is To Be Done With Our Charlie?," Portland Transcript, 1858 Nov 27
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "Witch of the Spinning Wheel," The Youth's Companion, 1864 Mar 10
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "Witchcraft at Deacon Wiggins' - Chapter 1," The Youth's Companion, 1882 May 25
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "Witchcraft at Deacon Wiggins' - Chapter 2," The Youth's Companion, 1882 Jun 1
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "The Yankee Girl," Hingham Patriot, 1848 Aug 11
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, "The Yankee Girl," Portland Transcript, 1841 Oct 16
    - "Those Beecher Women," The Hartford Courant, 2002
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin," in New England Monthly, 1875 Mar
    - "Uncle Tom's Cabin. The Original George Harris…" New York Tribune, 1870 Jul 22
    - Ward, Julius H., "Harriet Beecher Stowe," in The Forum, 1896 Aug
    - "The Writing of Uncle Tom's Cabin," The Literary Digest, 1911 Jun 10